build it together for a habitation of
God through the spirit this verse simply
lays the foundation that each one of us
when brought together make up the temple
of God each one of you are a stone in
the building of the house of God or the
body of God amen
our opening text starts our scripture
reading Romans chapter 12 verse 5
brought out the same point so we being
many are one what one what every one one
body in Christ and every one members of
another we together make up the body of
Christ or the temple of Christ in 1st
Corinthians chapter 12 verse 13 1st
Corinthians chapter 12 verse 13 the
point is further amplified it says
therefore by one spirit are we all
baptized into one Watts body whether we
be Jew or Gentile whether we be bond or
free and have been all made to drink
into that one spirit so according to
this verse it was baptism that brought
us all into the body of Christ or the
temple of Christ now the church as a
whole experienced a baptism and we find
that baptism the story of that baptism
if we go back to the book of Acts
chapter 1 and verse 8 Acts chapter 1
verse 8 the Bible says here but you this
is Jesus speaking but you shall receive
ones power you should not receive what
everyone power I want you to focus on
that word you shall receive one more
time power after that the Holy Ghost has
come upon you and you shall be witnesses
unto me both in Jerusalem and in all
Judea and in Samaria and unto the
uttermost parts of the earth this is
Jesus speaking to his disciples telling
them to go and tarry a true Salam
because they were going to be in down
with power from the Holy Spirit well
that event actually took place on the
day of Pentecost when the Holy Spirit
was poured out Acts chapter 2 Acts
chapter 2 verses 1 through 3 when the
day of Pentecost was fully come they
were all with one Accord in one place
the Bible says and suddenly there came a
sound from heaven as a rushing mighty
wind and it filled all the house where
they were sitting verse 3 and there
appeared unto them cloven tongues like
as a fire and it sat upon each of them
this is the beginning of the church this
is the beginning of the body of Christ
or the temple of Christ remember we are
talking about the rise of the history of
the man of sin and I'm simply right now
giving you the the beginning of the
Church of God in Acts chapter 20 Acts
chapter 20 verses 28 through 30 Paul
gives a warning to the body of Christ
gives a warning to the what everyone the
body of Christ and here is his warning
in acts 20 verse 28 he says take heed
therefore unto yourselves and to all the
flock or given her another word for that
unto all the what all the body or the
whole temple the body the church the
temple take heed therefore unto
yourselves and to all the flock over the
which the Holy Ghost has made you seers
to feed the Church of God which he has
purchased with his own blood verse 29
for I know this that after my departing
shall Grievous wolves enter in among you
not sparing the flock verse 30 also of
your own selves shall men arise speaking
perverse things to draw away disciples
after themselves so what is Paul here
warning what is Paul warning the church
the body the temple what is he warning
them off come on you help me out
okay he's saying be on the lookout
because in essence Satan is gonna attack
the body he's gonna attack the church so
Paul sends out this morning he says
after my departure Grievous wolves will
enter in well he goes further in this
description and I want you to turn with
me to second Thessalonians chapter 2
we're gonna read verses 1 through 4 Paul
is warning of an attack on the body an
attack on the body of Christ and in 2nd
Thessalonians chapter 2 Paul says now we
beseech you brethren by the coming of
our Lord Jesus Christ and by our
gathering together unto Him that you be
not soon shaken in mind or be troubled
neither by spirit nor by word nor by
letter as from us as that the day of
Christ is at hand now notice the next
verse let no man deceive you by any
means for that day shall not come except
there come a want a falling away first
and that man of sin that who every one
man of sin be revealed the son of
perdition verse 4 who opposes an exalted
himself above all that is called God or
that is worshipped so that he as God
sitteth in the temple of God showing
himself that He is God now if you've
ever understood you ever study bible
prophecy before which if you have been
in this church for any time you must
have studied Bible prophecy we know that
the man of sin represents a system it's
not one particular individual one
particular person it represents a system
Amen but the Bible says here that the
simplest system is signified or
symbolized by the man of sin of whom
there is a head of this system so Paul
here is saying that this man of sin is
going to enter into the temple of God
showing himself that he was
that is God meaning he's going to enter
the temple or he's gonna enter dog give
me another word the body Paul said there
is only one way that this can happen who
can tell me what is that one way that
Paul said this what happened it's in the
text verse three maybe we can put verse
three back up on the screen a what a
falling away he said the only way that
this could happen that the man of sin
could enter into the temple and and set
himself up as God is that their first
had to be a falling away
now that word falling away is the Greek
word that means apostasy in other words
Paul is saying there's going to be an
apostasy within the body and that
apostasy will give way to the rise of
the man of sin if you with me so far
just say Amen all right very good now I
want to take you over to the book of
Revelation we're going to go to
Revelation chapter 2 Revelation chapter
2 we're going to read through verses 1
we read verses 1 through 5 but just a
little bit of background in Revelation
chapter 1 john sees a vision of Jesus
Jesus is standing in the midst of seven
golden candlesticks and these golden
candlesticks okay guys let me say
something real quick don't don't don't
tune out okay don't think this is just a
lecture okay I am setting you up so pay
attention in Revelation chapter 2 not
that you were not paying attention
I'm just don't think I just saw somebody
nodding off or anything like that I'm
just trying to help you to just try not
to tune on go okay huh I don't know
where this is going because when we get
to where we're going you're going to be
upset that you weren't following earlier
all right so in Revelation chapter 1
John sees Jesus standing in the midst of
seven golden candlesticks and those
seven golden candlesticks represent the
seven Watts churches the seven churches
we
understand from our study of Bible
prophecy that these seven churches
represent seven different time periods
starting with the early church all the
way to the last day Church so the first
church Ephesus would be the early church
and then the last church Laodicea would
be the period in which we are in right
now so in Revelation chapter 2 this is
the message to the Angel of the first
Church it says unto the Angel of the
Church of Ephesus write these things
saith he that holdeth the seven stars in
his right hand who walketh in the midst
of the seven golden candlesticks I know
thy works and thy labour and thy
patience and how thou canst not bear
them which are evil and thou has tried
them which say they are apostles and are
not and has found them liars so pause
for a second we're not going to go to
verse three yet what is the condition of
the early church according to this text
just according to this text so far what
how would you describe the early church
just after Christ dies and he leaves and
now you have the outpouring of the Holy
Spirit what is the condition of the
church according to this verse what is
their attitude their workers what else
okay they're patient what else look at
what they're doing are they testing
others to see if they're truly
Christians yeah and how are they testing
them okay so what does that mean
yes so they're saying they're apostles
and are not in fact could you go back
just one verse alright you can go back
to verse 2 verse 2 it notices it says
you cannot bear them which are evil and
has tried them which basically claim
there are apostles and are not and has
found them liars let's go ahead and to
the next verse verse 3 and as born and
has patience and for my name's sake has
laboured and hast not fainted not an
answer question what would be the
greatest test of the early church to
determine whether someone was truly a
Christian or not it would be what they
what they believed it would be what is
your doctrine you master do you think
the first church this early church was
very strong on doctrinal doctrinal
purity yes how many of you appreciate
doctrinal purity how many of you fight
for doctrinal purity how many of you
would like to fight for doctrinal purity
well I don't really understand doctrine
by the way if it's pure doctrine we
should have it okay very good
so that early church is in a condition
where they're trying to make sure that
no one comes into the church that is
impure in doctrine that is impure and
understanding so they're trying these
different people who say they're
apostles and they're like what is your
teaching wait you believe what no no no
no you're not one of us
they have doctrinal purity amen
look at the next verse verse four it
nevertheless I have somewhat against
thee because thou has once left your
first love so let me ask you a question
what does it mean to leave your first
love to walk away from Jesus okay so
let's take that that description to walk
away from Jesus is it possible that you
can stand for doctrinal purity and yet
not have love for Jesus
wants you to notice this next verse
remember from whence thou art what
fallen pause for a second what did Paul
warn the church about he said there was
going to rise a man of sin but the man
of sin would what only would only be
possible if there was first a what an
apostasy or a falling away watch this
guys I need you to catch this point the
only way that the man of sin could enter
into the church was that there first had
to be a falling away and Jesus here
describes a falling away as a losing of
the church's first love if you're with
me so far just say Amen let me ask you a
question what was the church's first
love magic is love powerful so if the
church lost its first love then what
they actually lost was their power is
that right would you would you agree so
what was the first love of the church
how did we see their first love
demonstrated where do we see their first
love demonstrated Jesus absolutely is
the first love but my question is how
was that manifested in the early church
okay
check this out guys remember when Jesus
told the disciples you will receive
power what do you think that power was
that they received okay so we think it's
a Holy Spirit it's when the
manifestation of that power is when the
Holy Spirit fell on them and they began
to do what
they began to speak in tongues and that
was the power of the Holy Spirit but
love and listen to me the most powerful
demonstration of the Holy Spirit in the
lives of the disciples watch this come
back with me to Acts chapter 2 and we're
going to go to verses 44 Acts chapter 2
verse 44 to 47 and all that believed
were what does it take love for people
to be together
all that believes were together and had
all things what common notice the next
verse and sold their one possessions and
and did what to all men as every man had
what need verse 45 and and they
continuing every Sabbath every Sabbath
with one Accord in the temple breaking
bread from house to house did eat their
meat with gladness and singleness of
heart the greatest demonstration of the
power of the early church is not that
they began speaking in tongues on the
day of Pentecost or even that when Peter
preached 3,000 were converted it is the
fact that they loved so much that they
were willing to share all things common
and even sold their stuff to do it and
and the worship service was not from
9:00 to 1:00 o'clock it was every day
the love in their heart was so much that
they were meeting every day somebody
said last week how can we think about
worshiping God for 10,000 years in
heaven when we can't worship Him for
three hours on Sabbath
the charges demonstration of power was
in their love for one another their love
for other Souls but there was they were
falling away which means they began to
lose their fervor for four souls they
began to lose their fervor for one one
another and this is the only way that
the man of sin comes in is allowed to
gain entrance into the body of Christ in
Revelation chapter 2 the next verses
speak about a church called Smyrna and
in this Church of Smyrna there's
persecution going on and then we get to
the third church which is the Church of
Pergamos and here we find the church
that begins to compromise the church
that begins to do what everyone
compromise now how many of you know what
period the the Church of pergamus
represents who is one of the main
characters or figures in the compromise
that happened in the third church period
you also call this lame out together con
Constantine right Constantine facts
depend on how you pronounce it and
listen what happened in this time period
the church began to compromise with the
world did you hear what I just said this
is where Sunday worship is introduced
into the church this is where all these
different pagan traditions and different
things of that nature began to come into
the church but the question is why did
that happen and let me answer here is
reason why they happened remember before
the church have been persecuted yes
but the church began to get tired of
enduring persecution so when they saw an
opportunity to kind of get protection
from the state
instead of depending upon God they were
like you know what we're tired of being
persecuted
we're tired of enduring persecution and
so we want Constantine to protect us we
want the Roman law to protect us and
once that happened you began to see this
merge of paganism with Christianity are
you following me
so it was this that led to the
introduction of the spirit of the world
into the body of Christ and we read as
we read earlier that the man of sin
would enter the temple showing himself
that he is who God and this is exactly
around the time period where this began
to happen now
I want you to come with me to the book
of Daniel chapter 7 verse 25 Daniel 7
verse 25 let's get this up on the screen
quickly Daniel 7 verse 25 the Bible says
here he shall speak great words against
who the Most High what does it mean to
speak great words against the Most High
excuse me blasphemy making oneself equal
with whom with God okay so the this this
man of sin power would make himself
equal with God would wear out the Saints
of the Most High what does that mean he
would persecute the people of God and
would think to change times and laws
simply meaning he would be against God's
law okay so those three things equality
with God persecuting the Saints of the
Most High and would be anti-long now
come with me to Daniel chapter 8 verse
10 in Daniel chapter 8 verse 10 the
Bible says here verse 10 through 12
speaking of the same little horn power
follow me closely guys and it rocks
great even to the hosts of heaven and
cast down some of the host and of the
stars to the ground and stamped upon
them it's a it's basically the same
thing I was saying in verse in chapter 7
but watch this he magnified himself to
the Prince of hosts made himself equal
and by him the daily sacrifice was taken
away and the place of his sanctuary was
what everyone cast on notice verse 12
host was given him against the daily
sacrifice by reason of transgression it
cast down the truth to the ground and it
practiced and it worked prospered now
here is my question for you how does the
little how does this man of sin here
call the little warn in Daniel chapter
seven and eight
how does he prosper we've already talked
about how he came into the church and it
was because the church lost their first
love but now how does he prosper he
casts the truth to the ground now let me
break down what that means to you and I
need you to follow this closely the
truth being cast down to the ground is
very very important to understand if the
truth is Kapton cast down to the ground
where was it before it was where it was
up let me ask you a question when Jesus
died where did he ascend to heaven to
become our lot our high priest and I
heavenly sanctuary so when men wanted
forgiveness of sins what would they do
they would pray to Jesus in the heavenly
sanctuary but this system came along and
said no no no you can't pray to Jesus
you have to pray through us and once the
church began to buy into that basically
they had cut off their prayer connection
with God and when they cut off their
prayer connection with God it was only
in that way that the man of sin could
practice and what prosper grow more
powerful are you with me all right are
you with me are you sure the man of sin
waxed great because he cut off the
church's connection with heaven now
invite you to turn with me in the Bible
to second Corinthians 5 verse 17 second
Corinthians chapter 5 verse 17 the Bible
says therefore if any man be in Christ
he is what a new creature old things are
passed away behold all things are become
new how do I get in Christ how there's
something very specific that brings me
into the body of Christ you have to be
born again you have to be born again so
when I am born again or baptized what
everyone baptized I am now in the body
of Christ amen
and in fact Jesus or or Paul's tells us
something very important here because in
1st Corinthians 3:16 notice with me 1st
Corinthians 3:16 the Bible says know ye
not that you are Lots the temple of God
and that the Spirit of God dwells in you
so what are you what are you your the
temple of God which means you're the
body of Christ you are the temple of God
so let me ask you a question if you are
the temple of God do you think that the
man of sin is trying to sit in your
temple all right now some of you are
like wait wait a minute I thought man is
sin with an entity and a yeah and
something that happened to just follow
me here follow me here I want you to
notice Ephesians chapter 4 verses 22
through 24 if Asians chapter 4 verses 23
through 24 the Bible says here put off
concerning the former conversation the
old words man which is what corrupt
according to the deceitful nosov love
and be renewed in the spirit of your
mind verse 4 24 and that you put on the
new man
which after God is created in what
righteousness and holiness let me ask
you a question is the new man a man of
righteousness yes and you become that
man of righteousness when you're born
again in Christ is that so
so let me ask you a question if Satan
went after the body of Christ as a whole
as a church do you think he's also
wanting to go after the body of Christ
as an individual come he freezes chapter
6 verse 11 we were given a warning
weren't we were we given a warning to
put on the whole armor of God that we
may be able to do what stand against the
wiles of who why why does God want us to
put the armor on over the body
protection from who
protection from the man of sin pastor
pastor we need we know who the man of
sin is what are you saying how can how
can the man of sin enter into my body
come come follow me I want you to notice
with me Romans chapter 6 and verse 6
Romans chapter 6 verse 6 knowing this
that our old man is crucified with him
that the body of wants sin might be
destroyed and as a question is the old
man and the body of sin the same thing
yeah the old man is the body of that's
what the old man is made up of it is the
body of sin so we might say that the old
man is also the body of sin yes the old
man is also the man of sin what is the
old man
he's the man of sin let me ask you a
question what is the man I need to come
down here and do this now I'm sorry
what is the man of sin trying to do he's
trying to enter into the temple of God
showing himself to be God so beloved now
that we understand the way that Satan
operated on a large scale we're not
going to look at a at the at the micro
scale and see how is Satan trying to
enter your temple through the man of sin
you know how it begins don't you how
does it begin you want
how did the church allow the man of sin
to enter in they lost you know what
happens when you lose your first love
you're said you are preparing the path
for the man of sin to rise in your
temple imperceptibly
it wasn't like you know the the Church
of the Dark Ages appeared and said hey
we're the man of sin and we're going to
enter into your temple no it was a very
cunning it was a very subtle entrance
and in fact it was so subtle that many
people could not tell the difference
between the genuine and the counterfeit
it looked Christian y'all know it looked
godly it looked holy but it was not the
man of sin appears as something
righteous but is not remember what does
the man of sin do we talked about three
things he persecuted one the saints of
the Most High
what does that mean he persecuted the
saints of the Most High
he attacked them okay so why does he
attack them oh you attack somebody why
are you attacking them huh what is the
number one reason you attack somebody
they make you angry you don't like them
did a little more like the Saints of the
Most High no he doesn't like them Satan
doesn't like you guys check this out
guys the sign of the man of sin rising
in you Jesus put it this way first John
3:15 whosoever hates his brother is a
lot no not a lawyer a lot a murderer
what does it mean to wear out the Saints
of the Most High
he was persecuting them he was killing
the Saints the Bible says whosoever
hates his brother is a murderer and you
know that no murderer has eternal life
abiding in him listen to me if the if
the feelings of hate is rising in your
heart for another individual for a scene
of the Most High guess what it is
because the man of sin is in your heart
it is because you have lost your first
love and have set the path for the man
of sin to rise in your temple not only
does he persecute the Saints of the Most
High he exalts himself and makes himself
equal with God that's what the man of
sin sin does the Bible tells us in
proverbs 16 verse 18 pride goes before
destruction and a haughty spirit before
a fall how many of you struggle at pride
we're so probably don't even want to
raise our hands
[Laughter]
yes yeah yeah beloved listen to me
when you allow pride because pride is
making yourself equal with God when you
allow pride to dominate your life it is
a sign that the man of sin is reigning
in your hearts
so we persecute the Saints of the Most
High
he makes himself equal with God and he
is anti-long Galatians 5:14 says love
your neighbor as yourself
this is a fulfilling of the law so the
Bible says we should love our neighbor
as ourselves the Bible does not say love
yourself more than your neighbor but
love your neighbor as yourself now let
me ask you a question who was your how
many you were happy that you'd have
salvation how many of you were super
happy that you have salvation how many
were just like yes praise God the same
joy with which you have some because of
the salvation that you have that same
joy that you have for yourself having
salvation God says you must have that
equal joy and intensity to see your
neighbors have the same salvation I
don't know if you catch what that means
who's your neighbor
everybody in the church everybody in the
churches your neighbor right so we're
all happy that we're all in here and we
have salvation amen
law fulfilled it
no no because our neighbors are not just
one everyone in here it's your neighbor
across the street it's your neighbor out
there in the community which means
beloved listen to me if you don't care
enough about your neighbor out there to
go and to be a witness and to try to win
them God says you are breaking my law
which says love your neighbor as
yourself
you see they love it listen carefully
many of us come to church for our own
personal needs we're thinking what can
church do for me we don't come to church
thinking how can I be better equipped to
go out there and do what the early
church did in winning souls who were
quiet ooh
amen amen anybody else don't raise your
hand but no but I need you to understand
something when we begin to lose our
first love we big it is it is the sign
that we don't care as much about
soul-winning as we first did every when
you first became an out how many of you
remember when you first became an
Adventist now some of you were born
Adventist yes no you were not born that
interesting no such thing as being born
Adventist you get the idea right you got
to be born again I'll do understand it
but how many of you remember your first
born-again experience whether you're
Adventists or not your first born-again
experience
do you remember how the air smelled like
everything was just different like
just freshness and oh and you were happy
and you expected everybody else to be
happy around you and you wanted to tell
everybody about Jesus your neighbors
your classmate everybody needed to know
about Jesus and and you knew that you
had to tell everyone because Jesus was
coming again amen but then we began to
get into this rut we going to lose our
first love we began to you know not so
much care about okay yeah that person
maybe that they might be interested in
maybe not
God says listen when you begin to
exhibit these things when you in other
words let me put it plainly the old man
rises in you when you lose your first
love and that old man is the man of sin
you know what Satan is trying to do see
when Jesus comes again all who are like
him are gonna be drawn to him did you
catch what I just said all who are like
him are gonna be drawn to him why why
they like him because they've been
born-again they have the man of
righteousness dwelling within and like
attracts to like so many of us sitting
here thinking when Satan comes I don't
know what to do and I will never go
after him guess what if the man of sin
is in you you might be doctrinally sound
as as the day but at the man of sin is
in you if you hate your brother if you
don't care about those out there who are
suffering if you're if you've lost your
first love if you're making yourself
equal with God through pride guess what
you will be among those those five
foolish virgins who are closed out of
salvation but of it this is something
serious God is trying to show us
something here the man of sin cannot be
alive in you how does the man of sin
into you it is because you lost your
first love what is that first love that
first love very simply put beloved is
the power of God they Paul say that the
preaching of the gospel the preaching of
the Cross was the power of God unto both
Jews and Gentiles did he say that let's
get it up on the screen I want you to
see this first Corinthians chapter 1
verse 18
first Corinthians 1 verse 18 for the
preaching of the Cross is to them that
perish foolishness but unto us which are
saved it is the what it is the one
everyone power of God if you want the
power of God it is found in the cross
why is it found in the cross yes but
there's an even greater reason for God
so what loved the world that He gave His
only begotten symbol of it took power to
do that it's a power for Jesus to lay
his life down and that power was love
you see the man of sin grows can only
grow in a powerless environment if you
don't have the power of love in your
heart you are preparing the ground for
the man of sin to wax great in your
hearts this is why Satan is so bound on
getting us to to live in his principle
of hate of not caring for our neighbor
Romans chapter 116 the Bible says this I
am not ashamed of the wild gospel of
Christ for it is the Watts power of God
unto salvation to everyone that believes
to the Jew first and then the Gentile
notice with me first John chapter 3 I'm
going to go through these verses rapidly
they're all in first on chapter 3 and
chapter 4 first John chapter 3 verse 1
behold what manner of Lots
love the father has bestowed upon us
that we should be called the sons of God
therefore the world knoweth him
not because it knew him not notice verse
14 verse 14 we know that we have passed
from death unto life because we want
love the Brethren he that loveth not his
brother abide in what death verse 16
hereby perceive we the love of God
because he laid down his life for us and
we ought to lay down our life for the
Brethren notice with me verse 18 my
little children let us not love in Word
neither in tongue I love you let us love
in watts in deed and in truth because
beloved listen to me if you can love in
deed and in truth you become powerful
the most powerful people in the Bible
were those who loved unconditionally
loved in the face of hate loved in the
face of opposition look at Joseph he is
perhaps out of Jesus most of us he's our
favorite Joseph Joseph Joseph do you
realize what Joseph went through and how
much he loved
as many as received him to them gave he
what power to become the sons of God to
become a son of God beloved you need to
love you need to look your heart needs
to be so full of love and once that love
begins to fall away I want you to
understand you are leading way for the
man of sin to rise and the man of sin
will think to change times and laws
which means when you start thinking man
I don't like you guess who that is
speaking it's the man of Satan when you
start thinking in your mind when you
start changing God's law in your mind to
say it's alright for me to not go out
and witness to mind it it's alright for
me to hate my brother and mad at him or
her because when we start excusing that
we are changing times and laws just as a
little Warren does in reality or it back
in those days we are doing that in our
own minds the Bible says love your
neighbor as yourself and now I want to
read this statement to you because you
got to hear this for yourself review and
Herald May 13th 1902 visit your neighbor
in a friendly way and become acquainted
with them those who do not take up this
work those who act with indifference
that some have manifested that that some
of manifest will soon lose their first
love yeah do you need me to read that
again let me read it again and I haven't
even finished it yet there's another
cause here listen visit your neighbor in
a friendly way and become acquainted
with them those who do not take up this
work those who act with the indifference
that some have manifested will soon lose
their first love and will begin to
censor criticize and condemn their own
brethren
that was me dropping the mic just now
the reason why we wore by the church
wars within itself is because we're not
doing the work of loving our neighbor
and once we begin to lose our first love
we've only set the foundation for the
man of sin to rise in me and the man of
sin to rise in you and the man of sin to
rising you and now all these men of sin
are in the church just like yet no no no
no no why because we have lost or left
our first love the man of sin can only
dwell in a powerless environment and
that means an environment where there is
no love is there love in your heart most
of us will say yes in word how does the
man of sin rise in our heart it happens
not only when we lose our first love it
happens when we get tired of suffering
for Christ we get tired of enduring
persecution I'm tired of this so I'm
gonna take things into my own hands I'm
gonna find a way to remedy my own
situation in my own way and how many of
us have taken that path in life not
realizing that we were removing
ourselves out of God's plan for us and
now the man of sin to ultimately rise up
in our hearts and in our mind and turn
us totally away from God Luke 21 19 says
in your patience possess your souls
1st Corinthians 4:13 talks about how
love endures all things
love is patient love is kind Revelation
chapter 14 talks about the patience of
the Saints beloved if we are not willing
to endure that which which God desires
to take us through we are going to begin
to compromise and compromise sets the
found
for the man of sin two rocks great in
the temple
second Timothy 3 verse 1 through 5 you
need to see this for yourself this know
also that in the last days perilous
times shall come verse 2 for men shall
be lovers of their own selves covetous
boasters proud blasphemers disobedient
to parents unthankful unholy without
natural affection trucebreakers false
accusers incontinent fierce despisers of
those that are good traitors heavy heady
highminded lovers of pleasure more than
lovers of God notice this having a what
form of godliness but denying ZAR what
is the power the power is love because
God is love you may look like a
Christian you may defend the faith and
defend the doctor say no no that's false
doctrine no that's right doctrine but
that means nothing if you don't have the
love of God dwelling in your heart you
all do know and have met don't raise
your hands people who may know the
doctrines but don't have love coming out
of them so why a lot of our young people
are turned off from the truth because
they hear one thing and all they see is
hate but let me tell you something God
is gonna hold a lot of people remember
when Jesus said whosoever offends one of
these little children God's gonna hold a
lot of a lot of people accountable for
the example we have set before our young
people
alright I'm coming to a close guys so so
so I need you to follow just just a
moment longer and I want you to notice
this Matthew 21 Matthew 21 verses 12 and
13 Matthew 21 verse 12 and 13
it is not Matthew 21 Matthew 24 I'm
sorry it should be Matthew 24 verses 12
and 13 the Bible says because iniquity
shall abound the what give me another
word for love the what the power of Many
Robots cold because iniquity shall
abound the power of many were wax cold
and when you wax cold the man of sin
will wax greater in you
that's why Satan is out - just cause
iniquity - iniquity to abound so that he
can snuff out your love because we have
no love you have no power verse 13 but
he that endures to the end shall be what
saved this is one of the most shocking
verses to me in all the Bible
it's proverbs 28 verse 9 how many read
this verse he that turneth away his ear
from hearing the law even his what
prayer shall be an abomination you guys
this is a harsh
this is a hard text he that turns his
ear from the hearing of the law even his
prayer shall be an abomination why does
anyone know why in order to take a guess
how many of you read this first before
how many you struggle with this verse
listen
what is the law
yeah the laws one is love God says if
you are praying to me while thinking
that you can harbor hate in your heart
that prayer is an abomination if you are
praying to me while thinking it's
alright for you or even deceiving
yourself Kannada hate you I just don't
like you you know a couple Audis kind of
crazy you know I don't hate you I just
can't stand you as long as we don't use
the word hate we're cool hey God knows
the heart God knows what's going on and
he says as long as you do this and think
that you can pray to me
I'm telling you that prayer is an
abomination now Radha to you the word
used the word abomination it's very very
very ancient the word abomination if you
look up the word abomination it actually
refers to an idol an idol idolatry
idolatry or an idol so what is an idol
it's something that takes the place of
who of God so wait a minute pastor are
you telling me when when we pray to God
with hate in our heart we are praying to
an idol yeah cuz God says you're not
praying to me whatever God you're
praying to is a God that is okay with
you hating your neighbor hating your
brother and that's what that's not me
though that's actually the man of sin
that's you that's you praying to
yourself that's you making God in your
image and in your likeness and then
expecting that God to bless you you're
not praying to me no no the man of sin
is City
in the temple of God making himself God
determine this vision that that we often
read we've I think we've all read it
talking about the holy place in the most
holy place and how Jesus had gotten up
and went into the most holy place but
then Satan went to take the place take
his place in the place of Jesus and the
people would pray father give us your
one your spirit and did not realize that
they were praying to who say and and she
says Satan would breathe upon them and
unholy influence she said in that in
that spirit was light and power but no
sweet love no love
but our God says don't you dare think
unless you're praying to me about your
hate yeah then I'll hear that if unless
you print me about your indifference
yeah then I'll hear that but don't think
you can talk to me and you can leave
we're just buddy-buddy and you have the
man of sin dwelling in your heart and
you are hating and not caring about
what's happening out there and and you
are a not liking people for this reason
for that people that reason beloved
listen to me the man of sin must die did
you hear what I said the man of sin must
be put to death the man of sin must be
destroyed Jesus says in that same lesson
to the Church of Ephesus he says these
words remember therefore from whence you
have fallen repent and do the first
works remember the love you used to have
for God when you just became a Christian
remember from where you fell remember
the passion
remember the desire remember those days
how many of you remember those days huh
are you saying you never had those days
I sure hope you remember those days
remember those days he says repent that
means turn back to those days go back to
that time where nothing mattered more to
you than soul-winning not the color of
the Pew not how the lights are shining
and what's happening with the light is
not right on the screen what's going on
on the world is coming to an end
remember the days when the most
important thing and the only thing was
about Jesus and people getting to know
him remember those days and you are
going to see a difference in your life
remember repent and do the first works
and what are the first words the first
work is love it is works of love I've
got two more scriptures and then our
clothes you need to hear this the Bible
says in 2nd Thessalonians chapter 2
verse 8 and then saw that wicked be
revealed whom the Lord shall consume
with the spirit of his mouth and shall
destroy with the brightness of his
coming even him whose coming is after
the working of Satan with all power and
lying wonders and with all the civil
deceivableness of unrighteousness in
them that perish because they received
not the love of the truth that they
might be saved
it doesn't say because they received not
the truth it says they received not the
love of the truth there is a love
attached to the truth and when you try
to take the truth without taking the
love attached with it you end up falling
into this category the Bible says and
for this cause God shall send them a
strong delusion that they should believe
a lie and what is the lie
it is this Matthew 7 verse 21
not everyone that saith unto me Lord
Lord shall enter into the kingdom of
heaven but he that doeth the will of my
father which is in heaven many will say
to me in that day Lord Lord have we not
prophesied in my name and in thy name
cast out devils and in thy name done
many wonderful works and then I will
profess unto them I never once knew you
the lie that they believed was that they
had a connection with God when they did
not yeah me and God were cool yeah we
gods like I don't know you I don't but
you're not even interested in what I
have to say you're not interested in my
law you've allowed your first love to to
fade away so what can I even say you're
not even hearing me you are hearing your
own voice of god in your mind telling
you that we're good you're praying to
yourself you have become your own God
you have reasoned the way my laws and my
requirements and you have now put your
voice as mine you are sitting in the
temple of God showing yourself that you
are God but love it I don't want to fall
into that category I don't want anyone
in this place to fall into that category
so God says remember repent and do the
first works I have a question for you
today our first question is this how
many of you remember how many of you
remember it may not last long I don't
know but you know what the Bible says
that God is merciful and willing to
forgive the Bible tells us but of it
it's Isaiah 57 Jesus says here I'll read
it in your hearing
Isaiah 55 and verse verse 7 it basically
tells us listen there we go let the
wicked forsake his way and the
unrighteous man his thoughts and let him
return unto the Lord and he will have
what mercy upon him and he will for our
and to our God for he will abundantly do
what pardon beloved listen to me how
many of you know what it's like to feel
the man of sin rising in your temple
come on every hand in here should be up
Maya
my hand is office you all know why my
hand is up this week I felt a man of sin
rising in my heart and I was like whoa
what's going on here why are these
thoughts even entering my mind beloved
listen to me I'm pretty
you think our pastor knows me matter no
no no preacher to myself I'm letting you
know that I know what it's like to feel
that man of sin rising up and saying you
know what you are and you know listen
man it's nothing but the old man
but for some reason many of us fear many
of us give more reverence and fear to
the Pope than we do to the man of sin
here it's easy for us to talk about the
man of sin that the church as a whole
the papacy it's easy for us to put our
finger there but yeah this sermon was
not about that this sermon is about the
man of sin in here some another there
there are some of us in here today who
need to repent and return to the first
works and I'm gonna invite you to come
down to the front and stand with me I'm
right here I'm right here who wants to
come and stand who wants to come right
now and says yep the man of sin took me
away from God the man of sin led me to
distrust God and I went my own way and
today it's time for me to remember and
return to the first works I'm not gonna
allow him to dominate in my heart
anymore
[Music]
so lord please bring me back to my first
love
beloved listen come come stana doesn't
matter who's looking it doesn't matter
what people are thinking around you
right now it's you and God it's you and
God come stand if you need to stand you
may not want to walk down here stand if
you need to stand here I'll just want to
stand and acknowledge God I need you to
work in my heart I've lost my first love
and I need it back give me love for one
another give me love for the for the
people in my church give me love for my
neighbors give me that love Lord bring
me back to the days when my heart was on
fire and beloved listen if you have not
yet experienced that first love if you
have not yet given your heart to Christ
here's your opportunity right now you
let Christ into your heart and you can
have a first love experience and you
don't have to fall away so I want to
make another appeal if there's someone
here today who's saying yes lord please
give me that first of experience just
stand it's between you and God
God sees your heart he knows your heart
stands say Lord I'm gonna trust you give
me that first of experience
[Music]